(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.3",
"generated_at": "2026-07-07T00:19:42.184590",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 16,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
「Luminous Stairs」 鷹嶺ルイ 誕生ライブ
"Luminous Stairs" Takane Lui Birthday Live
幽閉利口 逝く前に
Imprisoned cleverness, before passing away
ユーヘイじゃ利口に難儀ダーリン
In confinement, playing clever is such a pain, darling
幽閉ストップ 知ってないし
Imprisonment, stop, I didn't know about this
勘弁にしといてなんて惨忍
"Give me a break," how cruel of you
人様願う 欠片のアイロニ
A fragment of irony that people pray for
だれもが願う 無機質なような
Everyone wishes for something inorganic
一足先に 始めてたいような
Wanting to start it a step ahead of others
先が見えない ヴァージンハッピーショー
A blind virgin happy show with an unseen future
無いの新たにお願い一つ
I don't have a single new wish
愛も変わらず おまけに
Love is unchanged, and on top of that...
ワーニング ワーニング
Warning, warning
無いのあなたにお願い一つ
I don't have a wish for you
張り詰めた思い込め
Filled with tense thoughts
レフトサイド ライトサイド 歯をむき出して
Left side, right side, baring your teeth
パッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa
照れくさいね
It's embarrassing, isn't it?
レフトサイド ライトサイド 歯を突き出して
Left side, right side, letting your teeth poke out
パッパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa
ハハ、you are king
Haha, you are king
You are king
無邪気に遊ぶ 期待期待のダーリンダーリン
Playing innocently, darling darling of high expectations
健気にも笑う 痛い痛いの消える
Smiling admirably, the pain fades away
無様に〇ねる 苦い思いもなくなって
Dying clumsily, with bitter feelings gone
ラララブウ ラッタッタ
L-L-Love, rat-tat-tat
嫌い嫌いの最低 泣いてダウン
Hate it, hate it, the worst, crying and down
毎度新たにお願い一つ
A new wish every single time
愛も変わらず ピックアップの
Love remains unchanged, picking up a...
ワーニング ワーニング
Warning, warning
無いのあなたにお願い一つ
I don't have a wish for you
張り詰めた思い込め
Filled with tense thoughts
レフトサイド ライトサイド 歯をむき出して
Left side, right side, baring your teeth
パッパッパ
Pa-pa-pa
邪魔くさいね
It's bothersome, isn't it?
レフトサイド ライトサイド 歯を突き出して
Left side, right side, letting your teeth poke out
パッパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa
ハハ、you are king
Haha, you are king
You are king
走りなさい
Run,
早く もっと 早く
quickly, more quickly,
悲しみに追いつかれないように
so that sadness won't catch up to you.
探しなさい
Search,
あかりの灯る道を
for the path where the lights are lit.
それは
That,
that...
まばゆいでしょう
...must be dazzling.
挑みなさい
Defy,
君の うつくしや 尊さを
your beauty and preciousness,
傷つけ続けるものに
against those that continue to hurt them.
眠りなさい
Sleep,
疲れたなら眠りなさい
sleep if you are tired.
神話を持たない
Without any myths to its name,
あの 星座のように
just like that constellation.
手を離したあと
After letting go of hands,
君は気づくだろう
you will probably realize...
指の形 太陽
the shape of fingers, the sun,
その名残りが
those remnants...
胸を刺す
...piercing your chest.
忘れたことも
Even what you've forgotten,
忘れてしまえ
forget all about it.
悲しみも ぬくもりも
Sadness and warmth too,
消えてしまえ
let them all fade away.
されど 今も
And yet, even now,
耳に残るのは
what remains in my ears...
ただ 咲いた 言葉を願うような...
...is just like wishing for words that bloomed...
さようなら
Goodbye...
Ah do, ah do
I do and you
踊りなさい 誰に笑われても
Dance! No matter who laughs at you...
淡い雪を払う
brushing off light snow,
絵の具のように
like paints.
叫びなさい
Scream!
心から叫びなさい
Scream from the bottom of your heart!
ここに確かに居たんだと 響かせて
Let it ring out that you were indeed here.
行き交いの空に 遠花火が滲む
In the crisscrossing sky, distant fireworks blur.
帰るべき家を探す
Searching for a home to return to...
長い長い旅路を
If you are to embark on
行くなら
this long, long journey...
奏でたなら その心臓は
If you play it, that heart of yours
最後のひとつまで君のものだ
is yours to the very last beat.
涙、涙、溢れる街
Tears, tears, overflowing the town...
同じ鼓動が君の周りをそっと 囲っているだろう_
The same heartbeat must be gently surrounding you.
さようなら_
Goodbye.
Ah do, ah do
それは一時のホームシックに似ていた
It was like a temporary homesickness,
無限さえも数え終えて_
having finished counting even infinity.
怪物のような世界の隅っこで_
At the corner of a monster-like world,
戦い続ける君は_
you, who continue to fight, are...
エルフェ、エルフェ_
Elfe, Elfe.
旅は続く_
The journey continues.
忘れたことも忘れてしまう前_
Before forgetting even the things you've forgotten,
悲しみも温もりも 消えちまえ_
may sadness and warmth all vanish.
今を、今を、君の言葉_
Now, now, your words...
硬く塞いだ手を願うような_
as if wishing for tightly closed hands,
さようなら_
Goodbye.
Ah do, ah do
I do and you
IRIS OUT
[Title: IRIS OUT]
ダメダメダメダメ
No, no, no, no!
脳みその中からやめろ
Stop it inside my brain!
バカと喚くモラリティー
Morality screaming like a fool.
Darling baby darling
半端なくらぶとときめき
unbelievable love and heartbeats,
浮き足立ったフィロソフィー
restless philosophy.
死ぬほどかわいい上目遣い
Those upturned eyes are so cute I could die!
何が司法に触れるっちゅーねん
What about it violates the law?!
ばら撒く乱心
Scattered madness.
気づけば等身
Before I knew it, I was back to my true self.
この世に生まれて君が悪い
You're to blame for being born in this world.
やたらとしんどい恋煩い
This unusually painful lovesickness...
バラバラなる頭とこの身体
My head and body are falling apart,
大世界
The grand world
ダーリン ダーリン ダーリン...
Darling, Darling, Darling...
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It is time to show the answer to you who doesn't know the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
To the end of the spiral that continues into the dream.
夢幻
[Song: Mugen]
生き急ぐ理由は 儚い未来手繰った弱さ
The reason for rushing through life is the weakness of grasping at a fleeting future,
それを強さと履き違えている
mistaking that for strength.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
Hateful, hateful, ugly, ugly,
月を隠すほどの
to the point of hiding the moon,
黒く 黒く 淀む 心
a black, black, stagnant heart,
君さえ居なければ
if only you didn't exist.
ゆらいでいる ゆらいでる 花のように意思を繋ぐ
Swaying, swaying, like a flower connecting our wills,
奪っていく 奪っていく 嵐のように心を裂く
taking away, taking away, tearing the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It is time to show the answer to you who doesn't know the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
At the end of the spiral that continues into the dream,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
生まれ落ちた運命を飲んだ 背負った数の名前を覚えた
I accepted the fate I was born with, remembering the names of those I carried.
爛れるほど 心燃やす感情
An emotion burning my heart to the point of festering.
憎い 憎い 醜い 醜い
Hateful, hateful, ugly, ugly,
世界を分かつほどの
to the point of dividing the world,
怒り 怒り 燃やす 心
anger, anger, a burning heart,
君さえ居なければ
if only you didn't exist.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでいる 花のように意思をつなぐ
Swaying, swaying, like a flower connecting our wills,
奪っていく 奪っていく 嵐のように心を裂く
taking away, taking away, tearing the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It is time to show the answer to you who doesn't know the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the spiral that continues into the dream,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞よ
Listening to the wailing of demons, it's the end.
この身に宿る万物で終いよ
It is the end with all things dwelling in this body.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
Weak people who entrusted the dream to others.
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The radiance of life is through many years,
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
in the setting sun illuminated by the twinkling of prayers.
千夜を身に宿し 解を押し付ける
Dwelling a thousand nights, imposing the solution,
枯らしていく 枯らしていく 夢幻の夜に花を裂く
withering away, withering away, tearing flowers in the dream night.
繋いでいく 繋いでいく 嵐に種を撒いて
Connecting, connecting, sowing seeds in the storm.
ゆらいでる ゆらいでる 花のように意思を繋ぐ
Swaying, swaying, like a flower connecting our wills,
奪っていく 奪っていく 嵐のように心を裂く
taking away, taking away, tearing the heart like a storm.
永遠の意味 知らぬ君に 答えを示す時だ
It is time to show the answer to you who doesn't know the meaning of eternity.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
At the end of the spiral that continues into the dream,
待つのは誰
who is waiting?
イェーイ
Yeah!
ということでね、ねねちに来ていただきました！
So, we have Nene-chi joining us!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！ねねたんです！
Happy birthday! I'm Nene-tan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
よく…抑えきれたな！
You did well holding it back!
なんかもうね、か、顔、顔はもう…
Like, my face, my face is already...
涙で滲んでいる！
...blurred with tears!
大、大丈夫かって？
"Are... Are you okay?" you ask?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
いやいやいや、ありがとうございます。こちらこそ。
No, no, thank you! Same here.
ということで、2024年の生誕祭はですね、
So, for my 2024 birthday festival...
あの、ねこさんがご出演ということで。
...we have Neko-san appearing!
はい！
Yes!
ねこたんもね、3Dになったということで。
Since Nekotan also got her 3D outfit now.
なりました！はい。
I did! Yes.
で、ねこたんが「いつか、ルイ先輩の隣で歌いたい」って
And since Nekotan told me before that she wanted to sing by Lui-senpai's side one day...
言ってくれてたので。
...she wanted to sing by Lui-senpai's side one day.
なので今日は、お呼びさせていただきました！
So today, I invited her to join me!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
いや、めちゃくちゃカッコいい曲を
Wow, we got to sing such a cool song together,
歌わせていただきましたが、皆さんいかがでしたか？
but how did everyone like it?
「ねこたん良かったね」って。
They're saying, "Good for you, Nekotan!"
いや、いいです、もう。ねこたんのことはいいんです。
No, it's fine! Don't worry about Nekotan!
「ねこたん良かったね」って。
"Good for you, Nekotan!"
そんなことより、ルイ先輩、ねこたん何回、今日重大告知もあるし。
More importantly, Lui-senpai! You have some major announcements today...
そうなんです。
That's right.
し、新衣装も。
...and... and a new outfit, right?
新衣装もあるんです。
Yes, I also have a new outfit.
出るんでしたっけ？
Was that coming out?
これね、たくさんね、ここのハッシュタグ、
So, we have this hashtag here,
#鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE ってありますので、
#鷹嶺ルイ超重大生誕LIVE...
それでたくさんたくさん、ポストしてくれたら嬉しいなと思うんですけど。
...and I'd be so happy if you could post using it a lot.
今日はたくさん、告知もありますし。
But today we have so many announcements...
そうですよね。
Right.
いや、ねこたん気になるのももちろん、重大告知のデカさも気になるんですけど。
I mean, Nekotan is curious too, but I'm also curious about how big the major announcements are...
新衣装がやっぱりね、気になる。
...but I'm really curious about the new outfit.
やっぱルイ先輩って言えば、こうちょっとダークネスな感じなのかなとか思って。
When I think of Lui-senpai, I wonder if it'll have a dark vibe to it...
ああ、なるほど、なるほど、なるほど。
Ah, I see, I see, I see.
暗い、黒系なのかな、みたいな。
...like a dark or black-themed one.
ああ、なるほどなるほど。そう思いますよね。
Ah, I see. That makes sense.
はい。
Yes.
ま、それもあります。
Well, that is part of it.
おお、それも！
Oh, that too?!
それは、ということは？
Which means...?
最初ね、あの、固定でも書かせていただいたんですけど。
At first, as I wrote in the pinned post as well...
はい。
...yes.
あの、新衣装は最初、サブカラー。
The new outfit starts with a sub-color...
え？
Huh?
で、ちょっと清楚な感じの衣装になっております。
...and it'll be a slightly elegant and pure style.
え？それもあるってこと？他にもあるってこと？
Huh? You have that too? There are others?!
はい。めちゃくちゃ大量にサブを用意しておりますので、最後までね、楽しんで。
Yes. I've prepared a huge variety of sub-options, so look forward to it until the end.
何かすごい騒いでる。
Something's making a huge racket...
おかしい。
How strange.
サブ！
Subs!
うん。もういいや、今日は来てくれてありがとう。
Yeah. Anyway, thank you for coming today.
わかりました。楽屋で応援してます。それでは！
Understood. I'll cheer you on from the dressing room. Well then!
あ、違う違う。そ、そちらは舞踏会会場なんで。
Ah, wait, no. That direction is the ballroom.
え？ダメなんですか？ねこたん。
Huh? Is it off-limits to Nekotan?
ねこたんは呼んでない。招待状もらってないでしょ？
I didn't invite Nekotan. You didn't get an invitation, did you?
もらってないけど。
I didn't, but...
じゃ、すいませんが、楽屋の方に、あちらから。
So, sorry, but the dressing room is that way.
えー！
Eww!
はい、スタッフさんお願いします。
Alright, staff, please assist her.
ルイ先輩、タッチ、タッチ、タッチ。
Lui-senpai, high-five, high-five, high-five.
ありがとう、ありがとう。
Thank you, thank you.
頑張ってください。
Good luck!
ありがとうね、ありがとうね。
Thank you, thank you.
はい。
Yes.
ありがとうね。
Thank you.
ということでねこたんに来ていただきました。
And with that, Nekotan joined us.
はい、新衣装もね、たくさん見せていきますので、最後まで楽しんでいただけたらなと思います。
Yes, I'll be showing you lots of my new outfits, so I hope you enjoy it until the end.
楽屋のねこたんも楽しんでくださいね。
Nekotan in the dressing room, please enjoy it too!
それでは、聴いてください。
And now, please listen...
ジグザグ。
Zig-Zag.
[Song: ZIG-ZAG
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Ayumi Nakamura / Takayuki Yoshimura]
寄せ集めて囁いた
Gathering and whispering...
「とりあえず」はもう飽きたら
If you're already tired of "for now"...
こびりついて離れない
...stuck on and won't leave...
メロディはだらだらだら
...the melody is just rambling on and on.
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember this odorless, flavorless life.
忘れたいから歌った
I sang because I wanted to forget...
ばかりだなだらだらだら
...it's just been a drag, on and on.
恨むことも
Resenting...
憎むことも
...and hating...
賢くない故にできなかった
...because I wasn't smart enough, I couldn't do either.
これが君の結末ならば
If this is your ending...
笑ってしまいたい<
...I want to laugh it off.
嘘 嘘 嘘 嘘 嘘
Lies, lies, lies, lies, lies...
うそつき
...you liar.
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと乗せちゃって
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, adding a bit of a miracle to it.
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 たちが悪いわね
I've had enough, no, no, no, no, that's malicious, isn't it?
来ない 来ない 来ない 来ないな おかしなとこ全部えぐり取って
It's not coming, not coming, not coming, gouge out all the strange parts.
悪評だって結構
Even a bad reputation is fine,
好きに呼んでいいよ
you can call me whatever you like.
トラウマにバイバイしたいの
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma.
捨てて 捨てて 捨てて 捨てて
Cast it away, cast it away, cast it away.
私 甘え上手になれなかった
I couldn't be good at pampering...
可愛げとかが足りなかった
...and I lacked any charm.
後悔か？
Is it regret?
うるさいよ、もう
Shut up already.
過去は過去だと割り切っちゃえば
If I just accept that the past is the past...
きっといいことあるさとか
...and believe "surely good things will happen"...
これくらい
...this much...
百も承知だ だらだらだら
...I know all too well, going on and on.
願うことも
Wishing...
祈ることも
...and praying...
許されないから黒く染めた
...aren't allowed, so I dyed them black.
元の色も思い出せない
I can't even remember the original color...
狂った運命の
...of this crazy fate's...
糸 糸 糸 糸
...thread, thread, thread, thread.
痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって保存
It hurts, hurts, hurts, hurts, pretending to be a tragic heroine.
もう嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 諦めちゃえばいいのに
I've had enough, no, no, no, no, though it'd be easier to just give up.
会いたい 会いたい 会いたい 会いたいな
I want to see you, see you, see you, see you...
深呼吸 ああ こんがらがっちゃって
...deep breath, ah, getting all tangled up.
明日またきっと
Tomorrow, surely again...
壊すけどいいの？
I'm going to break it, is that okay?
トラウマ退治の Death, Death, de, Death!
Death, Death, de, Death to conquer trauma!
夢の中で君と手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I am holding hands with you
何も知らないあの頃の二人のままで
Just like we were back then, knowing nothing
でも分かっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know that I will wake up soon
それならばいっそ君の手でそっと 殺して
If that's the case, I'd rather you gently... kill me
ほら 今、今、今、今
Look, now, now, now, now
委ねたい、たい、たい、たいな
I want to surrender, -der, -der, -der...
奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃってもいい？
Can I wish for a little bit of a miracle?
いや、いや、いや、いや、いや
No, no, no, no, no
たちが悪いわ らい、らい、らい、らいな
It's so toxic... -lai, -lai, -lai, -laina
おかしなとこ全部えぐりとって
Scoop out all the strange parts
拍手喝采で結構
Applause is perfectly fine
好きに呼んでいいよ
You can call me whatever you like
トラウマにバイバイしたいの
I want to say goodbye to trauma
Death, Death, de, Death, Death, de, Death
世界欺く揺るぎない正義
An unwavering justice that deceives the world
ほどいて真実この手の中
Unraveling the truth into these hands
アイのシナリオ
[Song: Ai no Scenario]
大胆不敵な影が華麗に踊る
A fearless shadow dances gracefully
君が隠してる秘密いつか聞かせてよ
Tell me someday the secret you're hiding
伸ばした手で触れる事は誰もできない
No one can touch you with an outstretched hand
君が隠してる世界僕に見させてよ
Let me see the world you're hiding
揺れる難解な心
A swaying, complex heart
解き明かして奪うその瞳
Those eyes that solve and steal it away
不安がって泣いてたって見つけらんないよ
Even if you're anxious and crying, you won't find it
狙う真実はどこへ消えた
Where has the targeted truth vanished to?
たとえ世界欺く解答（こたえ）だとしても
Even if it's an answer that deceives the world
「信じて」差し出す掌保存
“Trust me,” I say, holding out my palm
たとえ世界を敵に回したとしても
Even if I make the world my enemy,
「信じて」差し出す掌
"Believe in me," the palm I reach out,
決して離さない 答えは届いた
I'll never let go, the answer has arrived,
結んだ運命 この手の中
The tied destiny is in my hands.
繰り返された 後悔だとしても
Even if it is a repeated regret,
決して逃げない 怖くはないから
I'll never run, because I'm not afraid,
抗うんだ
I will resist.
何度も 何度も
Again and again,
走り続けるよ
I will keep on running.
Wake up! 闘志新生
Wake up! A newborn fighting spirit,
Shift up! ギア回して
Shift up! Shift the gears,
Speed up! 限界叩いて
Speed up! Pushing the limits,
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
Jump up! 天辺へ
Jump up! To the top,
Turn up! 声合わせて
Turn up! Raise our voices together,
Dream on! 未来繋いで
Dream on! Connect the future,
U.M.A. NEW WORLD!!
最高潮コンディション 闘志ガンガン尖らせていこう
In peak condition, let's fire up our fighting spirit!
栄光のチャンピオン 虎視眈々と狙っていこう
Glancing at the glorious champion, let's keep a vigilant eye!
ハイペースよりマイペース 気合レースに猛集中
My pace over high pace, focus intensely on the spirited race!
駆けるシグナルは限界 ハートに火をつけ U.M.A. Let's go!
The running signal is at its limit, ignite the heart, U.M.A. Let's go!
最高潮アンビション ぶつかり合ってガチ勝負 絶好のチャンスを 全力出して掴んでいこう
Clashing in a serious showdown with peak ambition, let's give it all to seize this perfect chance!
ハイペースよりマイペース 気合レースに猛集中
My pace over high pace, focus intensely on the spirited race!
掛けるウォームアップはセット完了 勝ち上がっていこう
Warm-up is all set, let's rise to the top and win!
友と二人 競い合った 風の中でも
Competing together, even through the wind,
大きな背中追いかけてた 雨の中でも
Chasing after that big back, even through the rain,
何百何千回と 積み重ねてきた
Hundreds and thousands of times we've accumulated,
だからどこまでも遠く どこまでも高く 誰よりも早く 誰よりも強く
So farther than anyone, higher than anyone, faster than anyone, stronger than anyone!
さあ 今
Now, at this moment,
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
these running feelings can no longer be stopped!
誰にも渡せないゴールまで
Until the goal that I won't hand over to anyone,
弱気な気持ち蹴飛ばして 強く戦う ずっと
kick away the timid feelings, I'll fight strongly forever!
立ち上がって 走り抜け
Stand up and run through!
鳴り出した鼓動はもう収まらない
The heartbeat that started to ring will not settle down!
最後まで全力疾走 レースを駆けて
Sprinting with full power until the end, running through the race,
頂点へと手を伸ばして 限界さえ超えてゆけ
reach out to the top and go beyond even the limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へ
Overtake the legend and go towards victory!
友と二人 競い合った あの喜びも
The joy of competing with you,
大きな背中追いかけてた あの憧れも
and that admiration as I chased your big back,
何千万回生まれ変わっても 何度でも 何度でも
no matter how many millions of times I am reborn, again and again,
走り続けるよ
I'll keep on running.
駆け出した思いはもう止まらない
This running feelings can no longer be stopped!
誰もが夢に見た未来まで
Until the future everyone dreamed of,
弱気な気持ち蹴飛ばして 想い抱いてずっと
kick away the timid feelings, holding my feelings forever,
すべてを繋いでゆけ
connect everything together!
さあ 今
Now, at this moment,
鳴り出した鼓動はもう収まらない
the heartbeat that started to ring will not settle down!
最後まで全力疾走 レースを駆けて
Sprinting with full power until the end, running through the race,
頂点へと手を伸ばして 限界さえ超えてゆけ
reach out to the top and go beyond even the limits!
伝説を追い越して 勝利へ
Overtake the legend and go towards victory!
友と二人 競い合った あの喜びも
The joy of competing with you,
大きな背中追いかけてた あの憧れも
and that admiration as I chased your big back,
何千万回生まれ変わっても 何度でも 何度でも
no matter how many millions of times I am reborn, again and again,
走り続けるよ
I'll keep on running.
Legend-Changer (Game Size)
[Title: Legend-Changer (Game Size)]
呼び覚ませ 本能を 起こせ 感動を
Awaken your instinct, create an emotion,
突き進め 頂上へと 叫べ ブレイブ・ハート
push forward to the top, scream "Brave Heart"!
Woah-oh-oh-oh
Brave, Brave, Brave out!
歯が立たなくて 悔しいのかな
Is it frustrating because you can't stand a chance?
錆び付いていた 身体はどうした
What happened to your rusted gear?
運命の扉 開いたんだ
The gate of destiny has opened,
目を離すな 歴史を塗り替えてやるさ
don't look away, we'll rewrite history!
段 段 段 段 上がってゆく
Going up step by step,
歓声 巻き起こす 時
the moment cheers break out,
段 段 段 段 迫ってくる
closing in step by step,
あと少し 攻め合う シンパシー
just a little more, clashing sympathy.
挑みたい
I want to challenge,
掴みたい
I want to seize it!
Fight on! Fight on!
生きてみたい
I want to live
伝えてみたい
I want to convey
革命の火蓋切って
Fire the opening gun of revolution
伝説の旗掲げて 行こう さあ
Raise the legendary flag and let's go, come on!
Legend-Changer の海に飛び込んで
Plunge into the sea of Legend-Changer,
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
and become the one who starts the craze!
Legend-Changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-Changer, let's go boldly!
醒ませ本能を
Awaken your instincts,
起こせ感動を
create excitement!
伝説刻んで
Carve out a legend,
大地蹴って蹴って蹴って Break!
kick, kick, kick the earth, break!
長い長い夢の旅路を
This long, long journey of dreams,
一歩また一歩と 確実に進んでいく
step by step, we surely march forward.
鋭い眼差しで見据える先に
Believing that at the end of this sharp gaze,
みんなの笑顔があると信じて
everyone's smile will be there,
さあ行こう 高鳴る...!
let's go! Throbbing...!
無数の眼差しに 見る栄光を
Make the glory seen in countless gazes
憧れにして 終わらせるな
your aspiration, and never let it end!
託された夢が隙を切って
The entrusted dream cuts through the gaps,
今私の闘志へと 変わっていく
and now it turns into my fighting spirit.
さあ Legend-Changer の海に飛び込んで
Come, plunge into the sea of Legend-Changer,
熱狂起こす当事者になれ
and become the one who starts the craze!
Legend-Changer 大胆に行こうぜ
Legend-Changer, let's go boldly!
醒ませ本能を
Awaken your instincts,
起こせ感動を
create excitement!
伝説刻んで
Carve out a legend,
大地蹴って蹴って蹴って Break!
kick, kick, kick the earth, break!
Wow...
Break, break, break out!
Yeah!
もう救えない スクラップばかりのアルペジオ
No saving it now, an arpeggio of nothing but scrap metal
チープな青春も お涙も それすら無いもんな
A cheap youth, and even tears, we don't even have those
相当に笑えない コメディのワンシーンもままならない
Quite unlaughable, we can't even manage a single scene of a comedy
冷めたチャウダーを ただ混ぜ合わせた さもそんな人生さ
Just mixing cold chowder, such is life
掛け違えたボタンの身なりを
The appearance of mismatched buttons...
いつのいつまで見ぬ振りしようか
How long shall we pretend not to see?
そうかい 抗弁のしようもないな
Is that so? There's no way to protest
たまたま火事場に逃げ込んで
Accidentally running into a fire,
善かれと油を放り込んで
throwing in oil thinking it was for the best,
生活も計画も 全部がポテトになっていく
daily life, plans, everything is becoming a potato!
ぐつぐつ明日が泡吹いて
Simmering, tomorrow bubbles over,
白目のままに茹で上がって
boiling up with eyes rolled back,
将来像 成功法 全部がポテトになっていく
future vision, successful methods, everything is becoming a potato!
このままみんなで散り散らかして
Scattering all over the place like this,
泥々に未来を溶かして
melting the future into a muddy mess,
そんな暮らしのままで KUSHA-KUSHAになっていこうぜ
living that kind of life, let's get crumpled up!
もう時間がない 我々に見下す権利などない
There is no more time, we have no right to look down on anyone
有象無象が発した ブーイングも 今なら勲章さ
The booing emitted by the rabble is now a medal of honor
相当に笑えない 誰がどう言わざるを得ない
Quite unlaughable, whoever has no choice but to say so
バカの一つ覚えのように空回って ただバターになっている
Running in circles like a fool's only trick, just turning into butter
始めはこんなつもりじゃなかった 誰か信じてくれやしないか
It wasn't supposed to be like this at first, won't anyone believe me?
一切 反証の余地はないが
There's absolutely no room for disproof, though...
あたかも何も知らぬ顔で
Acting as if knowing nothing at all,
ここぞと薪を投げ込んで
throwing in firewood at the perfect moment,
生活も計画も 全部がポテトになっていく
daily life, plans, everything is becoming a potato!
こんがり明日が煮え切って
The crispy tomorrow boils thoroughly,
姿見えぬほど燃え上がって
burning up until it's out of sight,
将来像 成功法 全部がポテトになっていく
future vision, successful methods, everything is becoming a potato!
このままみんなで散り散らかして
Scattering all over the place like this,
泥々に未来を溶かして
melting the future into a muddy mess,
そんなボウルの中で憂さ晴らしだとかしようぜ
let's blow off some steam inside that bowl,
そんな暮らしのままで KUSHA-KUSHAになっていこうぜ
living that kind of life, let's get crumpled up!
Welcome to the Wonderland
ここからは誰もがミーハー
Everyone is a follower from here on
How are you doing, Miss?
Put your temperance by the moonlight
どうせあがいても無駄
No matter how much you struggle, it's useless
死ぬまで帰れない
You can't go home until you die
不気味な猫が黒の中で笑う
A creepy cat smiles in the darkness
「こんなにも濡れてるじゃないか」
"Aren't you so wet already?"
官能へ響く声にそっと耳を立て
Gently strain your ears to the voice echoing with sensuality
まるでアリスのように
Just like Alice
殺さぬように
Neither killing you
生かさぬように
nor letting you live
壊れるまで愛してあげる
I'll love you until you break
快楽は媚薬なの
Pleasure is an aphrodisiac
どんな兵（つわもの）もやがて
Eventually, even the strongest warrior
犬のようにひざまずく
will kneel like a dog
This love is so insane
そう、これは夢の中
Yes, this is inside a dream
童話の魔女が出てきて御馳走
A witch from a fairy tale appears with a feast
お代わりならいくらでもあるわ
"There are as many seconds as you want," she says
妖しい仮面も擦り落ちそうで
As if her mysterious mask is about to slip off...
ねえ、いつまで子のままでいられる？
Hey, how long can you remain a child?
それすらも気付けずにいるなんて
To think you can't even realize that
Ah, dreaming...
Somebody wake me up
お平らげよ、そしてメリーアンは走り
Eat it all up, and Mary Ann runs
帽子屋がまたカラカラと笑う
The Mad Hatter laughs dryly again
誰もが皆、嘘で嘘を塗りつぶす時
When everyone paints over lies with more lies,
仮面の裏側が見える
the back of the mask is revealed
犯すように
As if violating,
汚すように
as if defiling,
散りゆく記憶を咲かす花
a flower blooming from scattering memories
甘い蜜が欲しいなら
If you want sweet nectar,
跪き地を這い回り
kneel and crawl on the ground,
その心臓（ハート）を差し出して
and offer up that heart
Yes, your Majesty. I'll dye our white rose for you.
Yes, your Majesty. I can offer my heart for you.
殺さぬように
Neither killing you
生かさぬように
nor letting you live
この狂気のディーラーさえ愛し合える
Even this crazy dealer can be loved
踊りましょう
Let's dance,
最後の夜（ナイト）
our final night
Queen of Heart
さあ寄んな 甘い街
Now, come close, sweet town
私をくれた人
The person who gave me myself
泣き癖 笑い合い
The habit of crying, laughing together
理屈のない喜び
Joy without any logic
曖昧 未完成の
Ambiguous, incomplete
過ち悟ったけど
I realized my mistake, but
それは恋の季節
That was the season of love
閃きは戻らない
The spark will not return
シナリオ通りのカルマ 飛び越えてきた人生
Leaping over a life of karmic scenarios,
望みがなくなって 愛だけ残ったの
all hope is gone, leaving only love behind.
それぞれの幸せ振りかざしても 倒れないふたりで立っていようね
Even if we brandish our own happiness, let's stand tall together without falling.
鮮やかでいてね そのままでいてね
Stay vibrant, stay just the way you are.
消えない幻
An unvanishing illusion.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜 エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
The Mugen Climax on this final night, carve the endlessness into it with novelty.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい 強くなりすぎたから
Because we became too strong to break, even when embraced.
あなたはわかんない おかえりからの孤独
You wouldn't understand the loneliness that follows 'welcome home'.
それでも無神経に 季節が巡っていく
Yet the seasons continue to change so thoughtlessly.
いつも褒めてくれた叱ってくれた 近所にいるような寂しくなるね
You always praised me, scolded me... now I feel as lonely as if you were just a neighbor.
忘れないでいてね 憧れていてね
Don't forget me, keep looking up to me.
消えない面影
An unvanishing vestige.
だからディズニー 時を超えて 同じ地球を踏んでられるわ
So let's cross time to Disney, as long as we tread the same earth.
魂だけ そばに置いてね 強く生きていけるの
Just keep your soul by my side, and I'll be able to live strong.
夢幻クライマックス 最後の夜 エンドレスを刻め 斬新に
The Mugen Climax on this final night, carve the endlessness into it with novelty.
抱きしめても壊れないくらい 強くなりすぎた 寂しい
Because we became too strong to break, even when embraced... it's lonely.
だからディズニー 時を超えて 同じ地球を踏んでられるわ
So let's cross time to Disney, as long as we tread the same earth.
魂だけ そばに置いてね 強く生きていこうな
Just keep your soul by my side, let's live strong.
はい、ということで、ゲストパートを見ていただきましたがいかがだったでしょうか？
Alright! And with that, you watched the guest part. How did you like it?
本当にね、あの、ゲストの人とこういうことやりたい！っていうのを、実現させていただきました！
I really got to make what I wanted to do with the guests a reality!
皆さん、出演ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much to everyone who appeared!
はい、詳しくですね、明日の振り返り配信で、いろいろ裏話だったりをお話しさせていただこうかなと思いますので、ぜひ振り返り配信も来てください！
For details, I'll be sharing various behind-the-scenes stories on tomorrow's recap stream, so please come watch that too!
そして！いかがですか？新衣装は！いかがでしょうか？
And! How is it? The new outfit! What do you think?
可愛いでしょう？たくさん、あの、差分があったんですけど気づきましたか？まあ、気づきますよね！
It's cute, right? There were actually many variations, did you notice them? Well, of course you did!
最初は白い衣装から始まりまして、そしてウマニューワールドではですね、あの、黒いパンツ姿で、階段から登場したんですけれども...
We started off with the white outfit, and then for 'Uma New World', I appeared from the staircase over there in a black pantsuit...
最初、みんな『あれ？ルイどこ？』みたいな感じになってて、面白かったんですけど、
At first, everyone was like "Huh? Where is Lui?", which was really funny...
なんかね、ウマ娘を知っている人は『まあ、あそこから来るんやろうな』って、なんか後方腕組みしてたのが、また面白かったですね！
It was also funny how those who know Umamusume were watching with their arms crossed, thinking, "Well, she's probably coming from over there!"
はい、え、メンバー、あの、このあとですね、21時20分から、メンバーで撮影会もございますので、
Yes! And after this, from 21:20, we will also have a members-only photo session...
そちらもぜひ、いろんな差分を見せていきたいなと思いますので、撮影会もぜひ来ていただけたら嬉しいでございます。
I'd like to show you various other variations there too, so I'd be very happy if you could join that as well!
はい、え、重大発表はですね、このあとあと2曲あるんですけど、え、今から歌う曲のあとで発表させていただきますので、
Yes, and as for the major announcement, we have two more songs left, but it will be announced after the next song I sing...
ぜひ、皆さん、ちょっと心待ちにしていただけたらなと思います！
So please look forward to it, everyone!
はい、え、じゃあ、次の曲はですね、鷹嶺ルイセカンドアルバム『ラピスラズリ』から1曲歌わせていただきます。
Alright, for the next song, I will sing a song from Takane Lui's 2nd album, 'Lapis Lazuli'.
『抗う君への鎮魂歌（レクイエム）』です。お願いします。
It's 'A Requiem for You Who Resist'. Please enjoy.
抗う君への鎮魂歌（レクイエム）
[Song: A Requiem for You Who Resist]
正しさだけ纏える術があれば
If only there were a way to clothe myself only in righteousness...
少しは救われるだろうか？
would I be saved even just a little?
その瞳へと問いかける
I ask those eyes of yours.
護るべきを捨てるべきと誰にかどわかされても
Even if someone tricks you into abandoning what you must protect,
心通わないなら
if our hearts do not connect,
それは虚言だ
then it is all a lie.
何も
Without...
捨てずに
discarding...
抗う
anything...
力なき亡者
a powerless soul...
その覚悟無き創造に
In a creation without resolve,
正しさなどない
there is no righteousness.
失えば失うほどに更に気高く
The more I lose, the more noble I become.
その意志で世界を恨め
Resent the world with that will of yours.
心が軋んで何度引き裂かれようと抗え
Even if your heart creaks and is torn apart countless times, resist!
か弱き一人を守り抜くための
To fully protect a single, fragile person,
この手の平がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
no matter how dirty these hands of mine become,
構わないさ君が笑うなら
I do not care, as long as you smile.
僕は何にでもなる
I will become anything.
浅ましい擬態 へつらうだけなら
A wretched mimicry, if all we do is fawn,
人も獣も何一つ変わらない
then humans and beasts are not different at all.
鎖に似た自由を
A freedom that resembles chains...
嘆いてはいびつに愛でるのでしょう
we probably lament it while cherishing it in a twisted way.
どうか君だけは
Please, at least you...
僕を覚えていて欲しい
I want you to remember me.
必ず君を自由へと誘う
I will surely lead you to freedom.
俯けば俯くほどに更に気高く
The more you look down, the more noble you become.
その意志で世界を揺らせ
Shake the world with that will of yours.
心が歪んで何もかもが崩れても抗え
Even if your heart is distorted and everything collapses, resist!
か弱き一人を守り抜くための
To fully protect a single, fragile person,
この手の平がどれだけ汚れてしまっても
no matter how dirty these hands of mine become,
構わないさ君が笑うなら
I do not care, as long as you smile.
何度だって壊してみせる
I will break it down as many times as it takes.
心から君が笑えた時
When you can smile from the bottom of your heart,
僕は報われるのだろう
that is when I will finally be saved.
[On-screen Text: 2026]
12.16
[On-screen Text: 12.16]
不安も、
Anxiety,
否定も、
denial,
葛藤も。
and conflict too.
私が歌で「反逆」する。
I will "rebel" with my song.
1st Live 開催決定
1st Live confirmed!
venue Kanadevia Hall
REBELLION Takane Lui 1st Live
ここから始まる。私だけの物語。
It begins here. My own story.
はい！ということで！
All right! With that...
私、鷹嶺ルイの初めてのソロライブが決定しました！
My, Takane Lui's very first solo live concert has been confirmed!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、日程は半年後になる...なるのですが、
So, the date is half a year from now... but,
半年後の2026年12月16日水曜日となっております！
it will be on Wednesday, December 16, 2026!
会場はカナデビアホールでーす！
The venue is Kanadevia Hall!
もうね、4月の末にホロックスライブがありまして、
So, we had the holoX Live at the end of April,
そして9月にネポックスがありまして、
and then NEP holoX in September,
そして12月に鷹嶺ルイのソロライブがあるということで、
and then in December, Takane Lui's solo live!
1年ね、2026年はすごい楽しめる年なんじゃないですか、ルイ友さん？
So 2026 is going to be an incredibly fun year, right, Luitomo?
はい。ということでね、ルイ友さんにはね、色々お話ししたことがあると思うんですけれども、
Yes. So, I think I've talked about many things with my Luitomo before,
私は前々からですね、今まで音楽活動を...
I have always felt this way...
で道を作ってきてくれた先輩、そら先輩だったり、すいちゃん、あずちゃん、
about the seniors who paved the way with their music, like Sora-senpai, Sui-chan, Azu-chan,
そしてわため、そしてカリ先輩のようにですね、
and Watame, and Calli-senpai.
ファーストライブから少しずつ、段階、階段を上がっていって、
Starting from the first live, stepping up the stairs bit by bit,
広い会場でソロライブをするという、そんな物語に憧れていました。
and holding a solo live in a large venue. I've always admired that story.
だから、もし私がライブをやることになった際には、
So, if I were to ever hold a live concert,
ファースト、セカンド、サード、フォースと、
I wanted to go from first, second, third, to fourth,
順々に会場を大きくして、ゆくゆくはアリーナという夢を叶えたい、
gradually scaling up the venues, and eventually fulfill the dream of performing at an arena.
はい、そう思っていて、ルイ友さんには、つねづねお伝えをしてきたと思います。
Yes, that's what I thought, and I believe I've always shared this with you, Luitomo.
そのためにね、定期的なソロライブができる活動頑張りたいなと思って、今まで努力をしてきました。
To achieve that, I wanted to work hard to do regular solo lives, and I've put in a lot of effort up until now.
そして、これからもします！
And I will keep doing so!
最近のホロライブはですね、結構より多くの人が入る会場での開催が多くて、
Recently, Hololive has been holding concerts in venues that hold more people,
私の夢はちょっと難しいのかなとは、思っていたんですけれども、
so I was starting to think my dream might be a bit difficult.
こうやって私の夢を理解してくださり、
But with everyone understanding my dream,
叶えるべく、まずは私の希望だったカナデビアホールにて、ファーストライブをやらせていただくことになりました！
and to make it come true, I'll be holding my first live at my desired venue, Kanadevia Hall!
おめでとう、ありがとう！
Congratulations, and thank you!
そしてあの、トレンドもありがとうございます。ありがとうございます。
Also, thank you for trending! Thank you so much.
ここからが、鷹嶺ルイの新章の、新章の物語の始まりでございます。
This is the beginning of a new chapter in Takane Lui's story.
まずはファーストライブを開催してから次を考えるべきだとは思うんですけれども、
Normally, I should probably think about the next step after holding the first live,
私はセカンド、サード、フォース、その先のライブへのビジョンまで考えております！
but I'm already envisioning the second, third, fourth, and subsequent lives!
はい。今回の生誕ライブのタイトルでもあるように、
Yes. Just like the title of this birthday live,
Luminous Stairs、輝かしい階段を駆け上がるために、そして、一緒にこの物語を紡いでいくために、
to run up those shining "Luminous Stairs" and spin this story together,
少しでも行きたいなと思ってくださった方は、
if you feel even a little bit like you want to attend,
次に繋げるために、応募したり、ライブを見てくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you'd apply or watch the live to help us connect to the next step!
ライブのタイトルは、REBELLIONになっております。
The title of the live is "REBELLION".
はい、REBELLIONです。
Yes, REBELLION.
はい、反逆という意味でございます。
It means rebellion.
私がいつも抱えている不安や、色々な否定の声、
The anxiety I always carry, the various critical voices,
そして、私自身の葛藤、
and my own inner conflicts...
これからも私は、それを私の歌で反逆していきたい、そんな気持ちを込めて付けさせていただきました。
I want to continue to rebel against them through my songs. I named it with that feeling in mind.
最高のライブになるようにたくさん準備をしていますので、ぜひ楽しみに待っていてください！
We are preparing a lot to make it the best live ever, so please look forward to it!
はい、ここからまた新たに鷹嶺ルイの物語が始まるということで、
Now, since this marks the beginning of a brand new story for Takane Lui,
アーティスト写真を作りました。こちらです。
I've created a new artist photo. Here it is.
はい、めちゃくちゃかっこいいですね。かっこかわいい。
Yes, it looks incredibly cool! Cool and cute.
はい。アーティスト活動の際には、こちら使っていこうかなと思っておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
Yes. I'm thinking of using this for my artist activities, so please look forward to it.
そして、ここまでファースト、セカンド、アコースティックとアルバムを作ってきましたが、
Up until now, I've released my first, second, and acoustic albums,
今回、ライブを盛り上げるための4曲、
but this time, to hype up the live concert, we have 4 new songs,
新しく作りまして、収録させていただいたミニアルバムも本日ライブ終了後に予約開始です！
newly made and recorded! Pre-orders for this mini-album will start today right after this stream ends!
ね、たくさん曲がありますね、鷹嶺ルイ。
Wow, Takane Lui sure has a lot of songs!
はい、「The LEGENDARY」という、タイトルを付けさせていただきました、ミニアルバムでございます。
Yes, this mini-album is titled "The LEGENDARY".
このあとに披露する新曲も入っております。
It also includes the new song that I will perform right after this.
完全生産限定盤には全員にサインが付きます。
The Complete Limited Edition comes with an autograph for everyone.
はい。完全生産限定盤には全員に直筆サインが付きますので、
Yes, the Complete Limited Edition will include a hand-signed autograph for everyone!
日頃の感謝を込めてサインを書きますので、ぜひ予約してください。
I'll be signing them with all my daily gratitude, so please pre-order it.
お求めやすい通常盤もあります。
We also have a more affordable Standard Edition.
こちらはちょっとサイン付いてないんですけど、
This one doesn't come with an autograph,
通常盤もございますので、ぜひお手元にとっていただけますと嬉しいです。
but we have a Standard Edition too, so I'd be happy if you get a copy.
今回のライブ、そしてこのあとに予約開始されるミニアルバムのハッシュタグは共通で、
The hashtag for this live concert and the mini-album starting pre-orders after this is the same:
ハッシュタグ「鷹嶺ルイの反逆」となっております。
It's the hashtag #鷹嶺ルイの反逆 [Takane Lui's Rebellion].
皆さんたくさんポストして盛り上げてくてくださいね。ビジュ良いっしょ？ビジュ良いよね。
Please post a lot to build up the excitement. The visuals look great, right? I know they do!
以上、ソロライブとミニアルバムの告知でした。
That's all for the solo live and mini-album announcements.
まだおしらせはございます。
There are still more announcements!
はい、おしらせと重大告知がございます。次は、お待ちかねのグッズ紹介です。
Yes, we have more news and a major announcement. Next is the merchandise introduction you've been waiting for!
はい、こちら！鷹嶺ルイ誕生日記念2026、ということで...
Here it is! Takane Lui Birthday Celebration 2026...
キービジュアルはですね、今回お披露目させていただいた新衣装を着て、ケーキを食べている鷹嶺ルイです。
The key visual shows Takane Lui wearing the new outfit revealed this time and eating cake.
久乃のらり先生に写真を撮っていただきました。可愛いでしょ？
It was captured by Hisano Norari-sensei. Cute, isn't it?
それでは一つずつ見ていきましょう。
Well then, let's take a look at them one by one.
はい！1つ目はこちら。アクリルジオラマスタンドになっております。
Yes! First is this acrylic diorama stand.
キービジュアルを使用した、アクリルジオラマになっております。
It's an acrylic diorama using the key visual.
ルイ友さんとですね、がんもも可愛く執事風におめかしをしております。可愛い！
Luitomo-san and Ganmo are also dressed up cutely in butler style. Cute!
はい、続いてはこちら。
Yes, next is this one.
新衣装にね、こちら、新衣装の、
On the new outfit, yes, on this...
はい、こちらとかに付いている、2種類のエムブレムをモチーフにした、ピンバッジでございます！
It's a pin badge set themed after the two emblems on this outfit!
色んな所に付けて、密かにルイ友アピールをしてください。オシャレでしょ？
You can pin them anywhere to secretly show you're a Luitomo. Fashionable, right?
続いてはこちら。
Next up is this.
新衣装をモチーフにしたポーチになってます。オシャレ！
It's a pouch themed after the new outfit. Stylish!
裏面はですね、メッシュポケットになっているので、缶バッジはもちろんのことなんですけど、
The back has a mesh pocket, so of course you can put can badges...
今回一緒に販売するピンバッジも付けやすいデザインになっております！
...but it's also designed to easily display the pin badges sold with it!
最後は、これ欲しかったんじゃないかな？こちら！
Lastly, I think you've been wanting this? Here it is!
はい、新衣装のショートパンツバージョンの、ホロフレと同じくらいのサイズ感のぬいぐるみです！
Yes, it's a plushie in the short pants version of the new outfit, similar in size to Holo Friends!
可愛い！
Cute!
ぜひこの機会にお迎えしていただけたら嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
I'd be happy if you welcomed her home. Thank you.
フルセット購入特典はこちら。
The full set purchase bonus is this.
はい、ポストカードになっておりまして、数量限定版と通常版がございます。
Yes, it's a postcard, available in limited quantity and regular versions.
数量限定版は、直筆サインが付きます！
The limited quantity version comes with my handwritten signature!
たくさん用意してお、おるので、ま、ゆっくり選んでください。
I have plenty prepared, so please take your time to choose.
販売期間はですね、少し余裕を持たせて、21時15分からカートオープンです！
As for the sale, giving a bit of a buffer, the cart will open at 21:15!
はい、以上、グッズ紹介でした。
Yes, that's all for the merchandise introduction!
そしてもう一つ、重大告知です。こちら！
And one more major announcement. Here it is!
なんと、私が夢見ていました、bayfmさんにてレギュラーラジオの番組が決定しました！
To my surprise, my dream of having a regular radio show on bayfm has come true!
放送日はですね、毎週金曜日24時30分から24時57分。
It will broadcast every Friday from 24:30 to 24:57.
初回放送日は、7月3日金曜日となっております！
The first broadcast will be on Friday, July 3rd!
Xでも初回配信用の、お便りを募集するので、はい、メールアドレスも公開しますので、
We'll be accepting letters for the first broadcast on X, and I'll share the email address...
Xのフォローをよろしくお願いいたします！楽しみにしててねー。
...so please follow me on X! Look forward to it!
はい。次の曲が最後の曲になります。
Now, the next song will be the last one.
先ほども紹介させていただきました新曲になっておりまして、名前は「Soar」と言います。
It's the new song I introduced earlier, titled 'Soar'.
ソロライブでもみんなと一緒に歌いたいなと思って、みんなが声出しできる新曲を作ってきました。
Wanting to sing it with everyone at my solo concert, I made a new song where everyone can call-out.
ナナホシさんに書き下ろしていただいた、爽やかな楽曲になっております。
It's a refreshing song newly written by Nanahoshi-san.
この後21時から、21時ちょっと過ぎかも知れないけど、ミュージックビデオのプレミア公開もあります。
After this, at 21:00—though it might be slightly after—the MV will premiere.
はい。楽曲は本日24時にリリースです。
Yes. The track will be released at 24:00 today.
この曲はですね、コーラスはホロメンが歌ってくれております。
The chorus of this song is sung by fellow Hololive members.
ライブまでにたくさん聞いて覚えてくれたら嬉しいです。
I'd be glad if you listened to it a lot and learned it before the live concert.
では早速聴いていただきましょう。
So without further ado, please listen to it.
はい、皆さんと一緒に歌いたい曲、「Soar」です。どうぞ。
Yes, the song I want to sing with all of you, 'Soar'. Here you go.
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
I will call you again and again and keep walking.
一歩踏み出したらもう未来さ
Once I take one step, it's already the future.
昨日つまずいた道も 今日からは近道だ
Even the road I stumbled on yesterday is a shortcut from today.
息をするたびに広がる景色
The scenery expands every time I breathe.
私を信じていいと言って
Tell me it's okay to believe in myself.
つぶやきも希望になって
Murmurs turn into hope...
あふれては声になって
...overflowing and becoming a voice.
何度目を閉じても消せないな<
No matter how many times I close my eyes, I can't erase it.
高く飛べるよ そうだろう
I can fly high, right?
抑えられない
I can't suppress it.
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one forgives the reason I spread my wings.
もう決めたよ
I've already decided...
迷わない
...I won't waver.
向かい風も きっと進んでる証拠だって
Even the headwind is proof that I'm moving forward...
君に伝えるんだ
...I will tell you.
どんな重力も 心までは
No gravity, not even to my heart...
縛れない 曲げられない
...can bind it, cannot bend it.
この手で確かめたい
I want to confirm it with these hands.
胸焦がした思いで
With the feelings that scorched my heart...
爪痕をさ刻んで
...I will carve my mark.
嵐の空模様 切り裂いて
Tearing through the storm in the sky.
もっと輝くよ そうだろう 叫べばいい
I'll shine even brighter, right? Just shout it out.
憧れより眩しい歌 そして激しい歌
A song more dazzling than longing, and a fierce song too.
いつか耳を塞いだ その両手がきっと翼になる
The hands that once covered my ears will surely become wings.
そう思うんだ
At least, that's what I think.
ゆずれない衝動
This unyielding impulse!
高く飛べるよ そうだろう
I can fly high, right?
抑えられない
I can't hold it back anymore!
羽ばたく理由を誰かに許されなくても
Even if no one gives me permission to spread my wings.
もう決めたよ 迷わない
I've already decided, I won't hesitate.
向かい風もきっと進んでる証拠だって
Because even a headwind is proof that I'm moving forward.
君に伝えるんだ
I will convey this to you!
何度でも君を呼んで また歩いてゆく
No matter how many times, I will call your name and keep walking.
皆さん本日は生誕祭に来てくださってありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to my birthday celebration today!
ソロライブ楽しみに待っててね！
Please look forward to my solo live concert!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
[手紙] ルイ友へ♡
みんなの応援のおかげで… ついに私もソロライブできるよ!! 本当にありがとう♡
[Letter] To my dear Rui-tomo♡
Thanks to everyone's support... I can finally hold my solo live!! Thank you so much♡
[手紙] もっともっと強くなって光り輝いて階段をのぼって、
いろんな景色をみせてあげるね☺☆ (任せろー!!)
[Letter] I'll get stronger, shine brightly, climb the stairs,
and show you so many beautiful sights ☺☆ (Leave it to me!!)
[手紙] 私の物語には君が必要です!!
これからもよろしくね!!
[Letter] I need you in my story!!
I look forward to being with you from now on too!!